doing what we do is nothing magical
right anybody can take a product put it
in a box and give it to a carrier it's
really about the relationship that you
build with those customers and being
able to follow through with what you say
you're going to do
we've known each other for many years
you are a customer
then we went through a process acquired
your business and now we work together
to make sure that this building where we
are today in Salt Lake City is a
world-class fulfillment center for
e-commerce clients right so absolutely
first of all thank you for the journey
together
um so talk to me about how you got
started in this business and what that
Journey's been like for you you have an
interesting story yeah it's it's been
quite a roller coaster to say the least
that uh my journey started back in 2004
2005. my brother actually started his
own Fulfillment company focusing
specifically on e-commerce order
fulfillment which again at that time you
know Amazon was still a bookstore and
eBay was really the you can actually buy
stuff online and have it shipped to you
so there wasn't a whole lot of Pick and
Pack competition at the time and that's
really kind of where I got my route
started and through the course of that
business it ended up getting Acquired
and that's what gave me the motivation
to start my own business which became
golden egg Solutions which I started in
2016. again with the focus on e-commerce
small parcel director consumer Pick and
Pack services but I also wanted to be a
little bit more Omni channel to focus on
1 B2B replenishments you know Amazon FBA
Hazmat products wholesale order
fulfillment as well to try and bring all
of those Services Consolidated Under One
Roof and it just quickly grew quickly
blossomed but not to say didn't come
without its own share of roadblocks and
headaches to try and overcome throughout
the process yeah but you did go from
startup to
um pretty successful group pretty
quickly sold the business in a pretty
pretty short amount of time so and I
know a lot of people they want to
achieve that right they're starting
their 3pl today or they started it a
couple years ago and they're trying to
grow to that level
what was it that allowed you to acquire
customers and grow so quickly when you
started
um if I were to narrow it down I would
really say it had to be the attention to
detail and the customer service approach
because really doing what we do is
nothing magical right anybody can take a
product put it in a box and give it to a
carrier it's really about the
relationship that you build with those
customers and being able to follow
through with what you say you're going
to do the communication is a huge
portion of that because when you are
starting a small business and when we're
bringing on new customers oftentimes
that client that is their livelihood
that's how they pay their bills that's
how they put food on their table that
they don't want to just feel like
another number in the books to a bigger
company they wanted to feel like this
vendor this provider actually has their
best interest and their best benefits in
mind and that's kind of the way that I
approached my business and grew it with
kind of a white glove so to speak
customer-centric approach to it yeah and
golden egg always had a great customer
reputation
and I know you
um had good success like the
nutraceuticals category and from what I
remember maybe there was some Word of
Mouth there also where you serve one
person and
it's an industry right people talk and
then they're like hey who are you using
oh not too happy oh well my guy's
actually pretty good let me let me just
give you a random cell phone and
um some clients come from there right
yeah so that's part of where my
brother's company had a lot of success
in was in the affiliate marketing
um industry specifically related to
health and wellness and nutraceuticals
so finding our foothold in that industry
early on was very critical to that
success of being able to build a early
reputation a strong reputation of being
a solid service provider within that
industry and yeah if you do good with
one client then word does get around
that hey who's who's your guy that you
use for this services and you know
luckily I was that guy right yeah no
reputation reputation is everything
right and you had a great reputation
um let's talk about
um what technology you use so when you
started sour ship station right how long
were you there what was that Journey
like oh it was a struggle so so you know
just for lack of options and ease of use
you know shipstation is a great platform
to be able to print a label but that's
really the extent of it and when you're
starting a small business that's really
you know kind of the main focus is just
getting product out the door there
really isn't a big attention to detail
on inventory slotting the accuracy of
when it comes in but as I continue to
grow my business those problems became
very real that a lot of feedback and
pressure from our clients of wanting
more visibility an actual customer
portal to be able to log into to submit
order requests to run inventory reports
to run General reports and just didn't
exist within the ship station platform
so through my own journey of looking at
different WMS software and different
systems that's fortunately where I
stumbled across ship hero and it was
absolutely a game changer you know from
the first demo that I had on the system
compared to other big providers that
were already available just the function
and ease of use you know the learning
curve was Next To None because it did
have a lot of that same user interface
at least you know from the aesthetic
standpoint that made it very simple to
navigate the system and implement it in
real time and being able to roll that
out to our customers was very quick very
painless and nothing but positive
feedback from that point that's great so
how many employees were you when you
decided hey I need to get a WMS there
was only four of us four walls okay so
it was earlier very early on I think it
was within the first year and a half of
starting up golden egg is when we
started to experience the limitations
with ship station and was part of that
you thinking like hey this this business
is growing I'm going to have I'm four
now I'm gonna be eight I'm gonna be 16
and be 32.
I need a game plan I need to get ahead
of this a lot of it was actually based
on the ability to segment client
profiles and have an easier integration
with their store profiles fortunately
you know the scalability from a user
standpoint kind of came with the package
but that's really what was driving that
decision was making sure that there's
the segregation of inventory portal
logins from a client standpoint and
making sure that we did the process
differently from picking orders to
actually packing because you know
shipstation doesn't provide that same
type of visibility it's just a paper
pick ticket which then comes up to the
employees memory of where product is
slotted versus having the system
actually tell you to go to a specific
location to pull an order okay so today
you're running a nice sized building
with a good number of customers and a
lot of volume what's your favorite
Shapiro feature my favorite feature is
probably the newest one that we've been
using which is the workforce hero
feature I'm just from a labor standpoint
and a supervision standpoint it gives
you so much visibility into what is
happening on the workforce floor without
having to be involved with everything
myself I can simply pull up the
dashboard and I can see exactly which
employees are clocked into which
specific task how long they've been
there whether or not they're idle in it
and it gives us that much more power to
focus our labor efforts into tasks that
really need the attention yeah I know
sometimes easy to check that when you're
not even in the building right just like
gives you a little like what's going on
there exactly yeah exactly so from yeah
management standpoint that is absolutely
a game-changing feature so let's talk
about people so we track
SLA and CPP right we have to hit our
service level agreements with our
clients and we want to do that at lowest
cost per package this building excels at
that last several weeks been top of the
charts uh consistent High performers so
that mostly comes down to it's people in
process right so let's talk about the
people's side a good team
team's been here for a while
leadership's been here for a while what
do you attribute the success of building
and maintaining that team here a lot of
it does come down to the culture and the
environment that we try and
facilitate here within the building
treating people the way that they want
to be treated giving them opportunities
for advancement and you know hearing
their feedback actually listening to
their concerns and trying to implement
changes where we can where everybody
benefits and that's kind of what has
really spearheaded the retention that we
have with our employees and a lot of
them came to us with zero experience
with not the best backgrounds and now
some of those are the ones that are
supervising and leading the teams which
is really kind of solidified that
culture that we do care about everybody
that we try and give everybody an
opportunity to succeed to grow within
their their own professional career and
it it shows with the team that we have
and their dedication and commitment to
working hard yeah and I've seen that
firsthand uh some leaders here who you
gave him a second shot right
um maybe some other businesses wouldn't
have taken a shot at them or give them a
shot a shot to succeed and they they
came from they're just picking up
packing through now managing all the
pickers and backers right so I've seen
that and
um and they're and they're super happy
like you could see
there's some people where it's like all
right they believed in me they gave me
the opportunity
um they treat me with respect and I'm
gonna bust my ass
um for the for the company and you guys
are you guys kick ass of that
um talk to me about Tyler how do you
hire him and and why did you and Tyler's
one filming this right so that um that's
easily hands down my uh best hire that
I've made to date but it was very
conscious the decision you know when
when I was looking to grow the company I
was doing it very strategically by
building a solid foundation and really
the only way to do that in a startup
company is to document and solidify
process because otherwise like
everything has to come from up here
right and then it's a peer-to-peer
training program and that's what I
really wanted to pull myself out of was
working in my business to be able to
work on my business in order to do that
I needed somebody with a operational
experience you know a good head on their
shoulders that was willing to to take a
chance on a young and growing company to
document process and procedure train
people on that roll it out and then
start measuring and tracking the success
of that to ensure that we're still
moving forward in the right direction
and you know fortunately Tyler was one
of those people that applied to it and
you know funny enough I almost didn't
hire him because he blew me off for that
first interview from his previous job
that he wasn't able to make it but you
know my my big heart gave him a second
chance Mr second Chad
and now Tyler does that same role
Nationwide so it worked out I've worked
out for Tyler it's a good good thing he
showed up in the second interview
um so if there was someone here I know
you help a lot of other business owners
um well it's just for the people that
are watching it who don't have the
opportunity to talk to you one-on-one
someone who's a new 3pl owner just
starting just scaling what advice would
you give him uh focus on the process you
know stick to the basics and don't worry
about trying to grow too quickly that is
definitely the thing that I found is
again once you can hold your end of the
agreement and follow through with what
you say you're going to do the
reputation builds itself and Word of
Mouth starts getting around that a lot
of business owners I feel kind of get
lost in the weeds of either continuously
working in their business and don't
focus enough time on building a solid
foundation and a solid process that
bigger larger clients can actually have
a stable base to grow from yeah I mean I
think the one thing I would
uh what I've learned from watching you
run this business is you didn't pick
like oh I'm gonna take this one thing
and
um it's gonna be the super sexy flashy
thing you just like step by step just
built it with just solid just solid no
you know I mean outside covid which was
a little crazy but you know no 100
growth years no hiring a ton of sales
people none of that just like every year
just a little bit better a little bit
better fill up the building make sure
you have good customers they're happy
they stick around and it's a successful
business right absolutely not overnight
but pretty quickly right yeah and that's
I think where having
culture the people behind it having the
process for those people to manage the
process rather than managing the
workload is all key to success and then
once you add in the technology piece of
that a system like ship hero on top of
that Foundation of processes and people
that operate it I mean that really is
kind of the the secret sauce if I ever
were to say one is people processing
systems and what I love about when you
talk to the people here shift
supervisors managers here about a
process change they will understand it
and they all have critical feedback so
they clearly understand the value of
process and also feel like they have a
respected voice because they're coming
back with like
well what about this situation what
about that how do we handle it in a
productive way just making sure so I
think you've been able to instill on the
team the value of them thinking through
process not just okay I do what I'm told
right it's more like I understand what
I'm gonna do so clearly you've explained
to them multiple times they understand
that and when there's a change they
understand the framework of how the
business is going to run and could say
they sort of hang this change on that
framework and say okay yeah this makes
sense I get it but here's some here's
some concerns here's some challenges
um which is which is a rarity I think in
a lot of buildings there's a little bit
too much you know pushing down of like
hey here's what we're doing yeah and
it's the same thing that you're doing
it's just maybe you're
um just you're just bringing them along
in the process a little bit more and
then it makes them super instead of
fighting the chain just sort of like all
right how do I understand how do I make
it better what does that affect me how's
my job going to be different what am I
looking for on day one when we implement
it
um which makes everyone win so
um yeah I'm always impressed with with
the team here and how they understand
process so yeah
um thank you appreciate the conversation
absolutely
[Music]